Ferargil Galleries
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Ferargill Galleries records
circa 1900-1963
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Ferargil Galleries
18.7 linear feet
The Ferargil Galleries records date from circa 1900-1963 and document the activities of this New York gallery that dealt primarily in American contemporary art from shortly after its 1915 founding by Frederic Newlin Price (1884-1963) to it's closure in 1955. 18.7 linear feet of records include incoming and outgoing correspondence with artists, dealers, schools and colleges, and museums and other art institutions; artist files; estate and legal records including papers relating to the Arthur B. Davies estate; gallery business and financial records; printed material; scrapbooks; scattered personal papers of Price; artwork; and photographs of artists, exhibitions and artwork.
Provenance
Circa 70 letters were give to the Archives of American Art by Frederic Newlin Price in 1958. The remaining records were donated anonymously in 1968.
Separated Material
Frederic Newlin Price loaned personal and business correspondence with artists and other records for microfilming on reels D321-D322, and N68-14-N68-15. The material was returned after filming and is not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Frederic Newlin Price (1884-1963) opened Ferargil Galleries in 1915 at 24 East 49th Street and 607 Fifth Avenue in New York City. Art critic W. Frank Purdy (1865-1943)was the President of the Art Alliance of America in 1918 and director of the School of American Sculpture worked at the galleries as director of sculpture.
Named from a combination of "fer" (ferrous-iron) and "argil" (clay), Ferargil Galleries dealt in wrought iron, sculpture, paintings and prints, and focused on exhibitions of work by American artists such as George Bellows, Thomas Hart Benton, Emil Carlsen, John Steuart Curry, Arthur B. Davies, W. Hunt Diederich, Thomas Eakins, Edward Hicks, Ernest Lawson, Albert P. Ryder and Grant Wood. Ferargil was also known for its representation of a group of contemporary watercolorists including Charles Dickinson, Phil Dike, Hardie Gramatky, Barse Miller, and Paul Sample.
In 1927 the business moved to 37 East 57th Street (later 63 East 57th Street) and housed a print room, a sculpture gallery with a fountain, and the main painting galleries.
In 1931 Price became the Director of the newly-formed Benjamin West Society at his alma mater, Swarthmore College. There, he promoted the arts at Swarthmore through annual lectures and exhibitions by contemporary artists and also acquired artwork for the college, primarily by Benjamin West. Price served as President of the American Art Dealers Association in the early 1930s and published a number of books and articles on artists including Arthur B. Davies, Walter Griffin, Eric Hudson, Ernest Lawson, Arthur P. Ryder and Horatio Walker.
Price closed Ferargil Galleries in 1955.
Scope and Content Note
The Ferargil Galleries records date from circa 1900-1963 and document the activities of this New York gallery that dealt primarily in American contemporary art from shortly after its 1915 founding by Frederic Newlin Price (1884-1963) to it's closure in 1955. 18.7 linear feet of records include incoming and outgoing correspondence with artists, dealers, schools and colleges, and museums and other art institutions; artist files; estate and legal records including papers relating to the Arthur B. Davies estate; gallery business and financial records; printed material; scrapbooks; scattered personal papers of Price; artwork; and photographs of artists, exhibitions and artwork.
Correspondence is both incoming and outgoing and documents the day-to-day activities of the galleries, primarily from the 1920s to the 1950s. Significant correspondence with, or relating to, many of the artists represented by Ferargil Galleries can be found here including correspondence with Bartlett Arkell, Thomas Hart Benton, Randall Davey, Hunt Diedrich, Ernest Lawson, Agnes Potter Lowrie, Luigi Lucioni, Barse Miller, Maxfield Parrish, John Pike, Paul Sample, Wells M. Sawyer, Theodore van Soelen and many others.
Artist files consist primarily of material compiled about artists represented by Ferargil Galleries, including biographical information, press releases for exhibitions, and scattered price lists and information about individual works of art.
Estate and legal records include estate inventories for the estates of Lizzie P. Bliss, Arthur B. Davies, and Dan Fellows Platt, and document several legal actions involving Ferargil Galleries. Of particular significance are the records documenting Price's involvement with the estate of Arthur B. Davies, including correspondence with Davies's wife, Virginia, and sales and inventory records for Davies's artwork at Ferargil Galleries and elsewhere.
Business and financial records date primarily from the 1920s and document inventories, sales, insurance, shipping, and taxes for the bulk of the gallery's operating years.
Printed material contains Ferargail Galleries exhibition catalogs and announcements from 1918 to the 1950s in addition to scattered printed material from other galleries and one folder relating to Arthur B. Davies.
Scrapbooks provide a more comprehensive and detailed history of the gallery's exhibitions, through multiple news clippings of press coverage, in addition to catalogs, announcements, and photographs. Of particular note is a circa 1908 photograph of Arthur B. Davies taken by Gertrude Kasëbier.
Scattered personal records of Frederic Newlin Price document Price's work with the Benjamin West Society at Swarthmore College and further reveal Price's interests through an inventory of his art collection and drafts and copies of his writings on artists such as Arthur B. Davies, and on changing trends and tastes in the art world.
A small series of artwork includes 6 pencil sketches, a print, 3 plans, and an Arthur B. Davies exhibition catalog mock-up with pencil sketches, all by unidentified artists.
Gallery photograph files include some photos of artists such as Emil Carlsen, Leon Dabo, Lloyd Parsons, Natalie Van Vleck and Lois Williams, in addition to 13 folders of photos relating to collections and exhibitions, and photographs of artwork.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1920s-1963 (Boxes 1-15; 6.0 linear ft.)
Series 2: Artist Files, circa 1920s-1950s (Boxes 16-17; 0.7 linear ft.)
Series 3: Estate and Legal Records, circa 1925-circa 1939 (Boxes 17-18; 0.3 linear ft.)
Series 4: Business and Financial Records, 1919-1956 (Boxes 18-21; 1.2 linear ft.)
Series 5: Printed Material, circa 1900-1956 (Boxes 21-22; 0.7 linear ft.)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, circa 1920s-1950s (Boxes 23-34, 40, OV 41; 5.4 linear ft.)
Series 7: Frederic Newlin Price Records, 1920s-1950s (Box 34; 6 folders)
Series 8: Artwork, circa 1920s-circa 1950s (Box 34, OV 41; 2 folders)
Series 9: Photographs, circa 1920-1950s (Boxes 35-39, OV 40; 4.4. linear ft.)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Bliss, Lizzie P. (Lizzie Plummer), 1864-1931; Carlsen, Emil, 1853-1932; Dabo, Leon, 1868-1960; Davies, Arthur B. (Arthur Bowen), 1862-1928; Parsons, Lloyd; Platt, Dan Fellows, 1873-1938; Van Vleck, Natalie, 1901-1974; Willams, Lois
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Art, American--New York (State)--New York; Art--Collectors and collecting; Art dealers--New York (State)--New York; Gallery owners
Types of Materials:
Gallery records; Photographs; Drafts (documents); Scrapbooks; Sketches; Prints
Names:
Arkell, Bartlett; Benton, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975; Davey, Randall, 1887-1964; Diedrich, Hunt; Käsebier, Gertrude, 1852-1934, photographer; Lawson, Ernest, 1873-1939; Lowrie, Agnes Potter; Lucioni, Luigi, 1900-1988; Miller, Barse, 1904-1973; Parrish, Maxfield, 1870-1966; Pike, John, 1911-1979; Price, F. Newlin (Frederic Newlin); Sample, Paul, 1896-1974; Sawyer, Wells, 1863-1960; Van Soelen, Theodore
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1920s-1963, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-15; 6.0 linear ft.)
  The bulk of the correspondence (approximately 75 percent) is written to Frederic Newlin Price, W. Frank Purdy and Ferargil Galleries by artists, dealers, and museums and other art and educational institutions. Artist correspondence is well represented with a significant number of letters from, or relating to, artists represented by the gallery including Bartlett Arkell, Randall Davey, Hunt Diedrich, Ernest Lawson, Agnes Potter Lowrie, Barse Miller, Maxfield Parrish, John Pike, Paul Sample, Wells M. Sawyer, and many others. Some correspondence relating to Price's involvement with Swarthmore College can also be found here.
  Found at the end of the incoming correspondence is a folder relating to an exhibition "The Circus Comes to Ferargil Galleries," and a folder of circa 19 letters regarding the authentication and disposition of Gilbert Stuart's Lansdowne portrait of George Washington.
  Outgoing correspondence consists primarily of copies of letters and memoranda written in response to the incoming material. The bulk of the outgoing correspondence ends in 1956 with one letter each from 1958 and 1963.
  See index for a partial list of correspondents in this series. The list also notes illustrated letters.
  Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent; outgoing correspondence follows, and is arranged chronologically.
  Partial List of Correspondents from Series 1
  Addision Gallery of American Art
  Addison, Walter
  Aiken, Charles Avery
  American Artists Group, Inc.
  Anderson, Karl
  Anderson, C. W.
  Andrews, Charles Sperry (includes illustrated letter)
  Arms, John Taylor
  Art Institute of Chicago
  Ashe, Edmund Marion
  Ashton, Leonard C.
  Bassett, Richard
  Benton, Thomas Hart and Rita Piacenza Benton
  Beresford, Virginia
  Bok, Hannes (includes illustrated letters)
  Bower, Alexander
  Bragdon, Claude
  Braun, Edith E.
  Brewer, Floyd E.
  Brooklyn Museum
  Brooks, Alfred Mansfield
  Bye, Arthur Edwin
  Byerley, Blanche A.
  Buell, Alice Standish
  Buller, Audrey
  Butterlin, Otto
  Calder, Alexander Stirling
  Campbell, Charles
  Cantine, Jo
  Carlsen, Emil
  Carrigan, William
  Cheney, Russell
  Clark, Eliot
  Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts
  Comito, Nicholas
  Conner, John R.
  Cortissoz, Royal
  Crane, Bruce
  Crowninshield, Frank
  Curry, John Steuart
  Daingerfield, Elliott
  Davenport, Carson
  Davey, Randall
  Davies, Arthur B.
  Julius Delbos
  Diederich, Hunt (includes illustrated letters)
  Dike, Phil
  Dix, John A.
  Dodd, Lamar
  Dows, Olin
  Dyson, Will
  Edie, Stuart
  Eilshemius, Louis M. (illustrated letter)
  Epstein, Jacob
  Faulkner, Barry
  Folinsbee, John F.
  Ford, Julia Ellsworth
  Ford, Lauren
  Freed, Ernest (includes illustrated letter)
  Gantt, James B.
  Gill, Sue May
  Gramatky, Hardy
  Hale, Philip L.
  Hamlin, Genevieve
  Hartley, Russell
  Hartmann, Sadakihi
  Haseltine, Herbert
  Healy, Arthur K.D.
  Heinz, Charles L.
  Herpst, Martha
  Hesketh, E.
  Hills, Laura C.
  Hoffman, Malvina
  Hollingsworth, Jr., William
  Holt, Jr., Henry
  Hopkinson, Charles
  Hoyt, Edith
  Humphrey, Eleanor B.
  Hurd, Peter
  Jennewein, C. P.
  Jones, Amy
  Jones, Janet
  Jones, J. Pope
  Judson, Sylvia Shaw
  Katz, A. Raymond
  Kellog, Jean
  Kent, Rockwell
  Kingsbury, Alison Mason
  Kreis, Henry (illustrated letter)
  Ladd, Anna Coleman
  La Montagne, Harry
  Lathrop, William L.
  Lawless, Carl
  Lawson, Ernest
  Lebduska, Lawrence
  Lechay, James
  Lee, Doris
  Lever, Hayley
  Lillie, John
  Lober, Georg
  Lowrie, Agnes Potter
  Lucioni, Luigi
  Macbeth Galleries
  MacLeod, Alexander Samuel
  Macouillard, Louis
  Merritt, Jesse
  Miller, Barse
  Nichols, Henry Hobart
  Oehlschlaeger, Frank J.
  O'Malley, Power
  Paradise, Phil
  Parrish, Maxfield
  Paxton, William M.
  Pike, John (includes illustrated letters)
  Prendergast, Charles E.
  Price, M. Elizabeth
  Puccinelli, Raymond
  Reed, Alma M.
  Rockwell, Norman
  Sample, Paul
  Savage, Eugene Francis
  Sawyer, Wells. M.
  Schaefer, Carl
  Scudder, Janet
  Shinn, Everett
  Shonnard, Eugenie F.
  Simmons, Will
  Smith, André
  Spencer, Robert and Margaret F. Spencer
  Tarbell, Edmund C.
  Tolegian, Manuel J.
  Townsend, Harry (includes illustrated letter)
  Ufer, Walter
  van Soelen, Theodore
  Whitaker, Frederic
  Wiles, Irving
  Wood, Grant
  Woodruff, James W.
  Yandell, Enid
  Yeats, Jack Butler
  - Incoming Correspondence (Box 1)
    - A-Ak, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Al, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Academy-American Collector, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1930s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Friends-Arensberg, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Arkell, Bartlett, 1930s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Armour-Arts, 1930s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ashe-Atherton, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Atlanta-Ayd, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ba, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Beal-Benton, 1920s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ber-Bes, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bi, 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bl, 1930s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bo, 1930-1950s (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bra-Bre, 1920s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bri-Bry, 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Buc-Bue, 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Buf-Bux, 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - By, 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Cad-Cam, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Can-Carl, 1920s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1920s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Carn-Ce, 1920s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ch, 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ci-Cl, 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cob-Col, 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Com-Coo, 1920s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Cor-Cr, 1920s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cu, 1930s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Da, 1920s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
    - Davey, Randall, 1930s-1940s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Dayton Art Institute, 1940s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - De Braux-De Witt, 1930s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Dee-Dev, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Di, 1920s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Doa-Dods, 1930s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Dol-Doy, 1930s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Dr-Du, 1920s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dy, 1930s-1940s (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Ea-El, 1920s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Em-Ex, 1920s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fa-Fl, 1920s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fo, 1920s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Fra-Fred, 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Freu-Fu, 1920s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ga-Ge, 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Gi, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Gl-Go, 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Gra, 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Gre-Gru, 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Gu, 1940s (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - H.-Hac, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Hal-Ham, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Han-Har, 1920s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Has-Haz, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Hea-Hee, 1930s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hei-Hes, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hi, 1920s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Hof-Hol, 1920s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hom-Hoy, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Hu-Hy, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - I, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - J.-Jex, 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Jo, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Jo-Ju, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Kal-Kan, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Ka-Ke, 1920s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Ki-Ku, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - La, 1910s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Le, 1920s-1940s, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Li, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Lob-Los, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lot-Low, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Lu, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ly, 1930s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - M.-Ma, 1920s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ma, 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Mc-Mer, 1920s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Metropolitan-Mey, 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mi, 1930s-1940s (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Mo, 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Mu, 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Museum of..., 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Na, 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ne-Ni, 1920s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - No-Nu, 1940s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - O, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Pa, 1920s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Pea-Pei, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Pen-Pet, 1920s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Ph, 1920s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pi-Pl, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Po-Pre, 1920s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pri-Pu, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Pu-Py, 1930s-1940s (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Q, 1930s-1940s (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - R.-Re, 1920s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Rh-Ri, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Ro, 1930s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
    - Ru-Ry, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Sa, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sample, Paul, circa 1930s-1940s, (1-2 of 4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
    - Sample, Paul, circa 1930s-1940s, (3-4 of 4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Sampliner-Saw, 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sawyer, Wells M., circa 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sc, 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Se-Sh, 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Si-Sl, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sm-Sn, 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - So-Sp, 1920s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
    - St-Su, 1930s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Swan-Swarthmore College, 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Swarthmore College, 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Swarthmore College, Benjamin West Society, 1930s-1940s, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Swarthmore College-Sy, 1940s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Ta-Ti, 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - To, 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Tr, 1930s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Tu-Ty, 1920s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - U, 1920s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Va, 1920s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Ve-Vi, 1920s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Vo-Vy, 1920s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - W.-Wa, 1930s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Walker, Horatio, circa 1920s-1930s, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - Wal-Wan, 1920s-1940s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - War-Way, 1930s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - We, 1930s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Whi, 1920s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
    - Wi, 1920s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Wo, 1930s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Wr-Wy, 1930s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Y, 1920s-1950s, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - Z, 1930s-1940s (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Re. "The Circus Comes to Ferargil Galleries," 1948 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Re. Gilbert Stuart's Portrait of Washington, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Illegible/Unidentified, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Envelopes, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, circa 1920s-circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1923, 1927-1940 February, (14 folders) (Box 12, Folder 2-15)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1940 March-1942 July, (14 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-14)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1942 Aug-1945 Feb, (13 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-13)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1945 March-1958, 1963, (13 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-13)
- Artist Files, circa 1920s-1950s, Series 2:; (Boxes 16-17; 0.7 linear ft.)
  Artist files contain material compiled by the gallery about artists including biographical sketches, news releases concerning exhibitions, printed material such as pamphlets about artists and their work, mailing lists of people who were interested in specific artists, lists of artwork including price lists, and notes on individual artwork including documentation related to provenance, authenticity and appraisals. The series also contains several pieces of artwork including an original ink drawing by B. S. Carter, Jr., inscribed to Price; 2 watercolor sketches by Niclaus Koni; an ink sketch by John Pike; an etching of Robert Burns by an unknown artist, possibly William Simmons; and a pencil sketch probably by Albert Stuart.
  Artist files are arranged alphabetically by name of artist.
  - Artists, A-L, circa 1920s-1950s, (15 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1-15)
  - Artists, M-Z, circa 1920s-1950s, (10 folders) (Box 17, Folder 1-10)
  - Artist Groups, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Estate and Legal Records, circa 1925-1939, Series 3:; (Boxes 17-18; 0.3 linear ft.)
  This series includes Arthur B. Davies estate records consisting of correspondence with Davies family members, including Davies's wife Virginia, and others regarding the artist's estate and exhibitions of his work relating to his estate; sales vouchers, primarily for work from the Davies estate but also for sales pre-dating the artist's death in 1928; and inventories of Davies's works at Ferargil Galleries, in other museums and galleries, and with individuals.
  Also found are transcripts and a telegram relating to the settlement of money for the purchase of Albert P. Ryder, Winslow Homer and John Singer Sargent paintings, by Charles Wharton Stork and Haverford College; a letter relating to a possible suit by Mrs. Marshall Field; inventories and appraisal of the Dan Fellows Platt estate; minutes of a meeting relating to Price selling paintings to Ferargil Galleries in exchange for company stocks; and an inventory of the Lizzie P. Bliss estate.
  - Bliss, Lizzie P., Estate Inventory, circa 1931 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Davies, Arthur B., Correspondence, circa 1925-circa 1939 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Davies, Arthur B., Inventories of Artwork, 1929-1930s, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
  - Davies, Arthur B., Inventory and Appraisal of Art and Literary Property at Day & Meyer, Murray & Young, Inc., 1929 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Davies, Arthur B., Vouchers for Sales, 1926-1927 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Davies, Arthur B., Vouchers for Estate Sales, 1929-1932 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Platt, Dan Fellows, Inventory and Appraisal of Property Belonging to the Estate, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Ferargil v. Stork, 1933-1935 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Mrs. Marshall Field v. Ferargil, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Price v. Ferargil, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Business and Financial Records, 1919-1956, Series 4:; (Boxes 18-21; 1.2 linear ft.)
  Records include inventories, invoices and receipts for artwork sold, presidents reports, statements of accounts, and insurance and tax records. Lists of artwork sold include information on prices and buyers, in addition to exhibition price lists, and lists of artwork received from clients. Notes and memoranda consist primarily of notes and press releases from other art organizations.
  - Addresses, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Art Service Bureau, Inc., By-Laws and Certificate of Incorporation, Drafts, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Bills and Receipts, Books, 1940s-1950s (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Bills and Receipts, Miscellaneous, 1920s-1950s (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Invoices and Receipts for Artwork, 1925-1939 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Insurance Records, 1937-1956 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Insurance Schedules, 1942-1956, (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 12-14)
  - Inventories, 1928-1932, (7 folders) (Box 18, Folder 15-21)
  - Inventories, 1933-1939, 1951, 1953, (6 folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-6)